<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID-19 | Cazorla-Artiles</title>
    <link>/tag/covid-19/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>COVID-19</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/EITT%20logo_hu3c46a502bedc4e379e43c7b35d8f26ca_249766_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/tag/covid-19/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Tourism Demand Model</title>
      <link>/project/itdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/itdm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This platform develops a methodology to anticipate international tourism demand by distinguishing the outbound market. The starting point is the construction of a baseline scenario that predicts the demand that would have occurred in 2020 and 2021 had the epidemic not existed. This baseline demand is affected by the situation with Covid-19 considering three effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The date of market reactivation according to the epidemic for each pair of origin-destination (based on an epidemiological SIR model);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reduction in income at origin and how it reduces the intention to travel (based on a panel data model);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reduction in confidence to travel (using post-pandemic travel surveys).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three effects reduce the expected pre-Covid19 demand and allow realistic adjustments according to the value of post-Covid expected demand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel de indicadores de COVID-19 en Lanzarote</title>
      <link>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A contribution made with Christian González-Martel to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cabildodelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cabildo de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;. This shiny web application pursues the understanding of the situation of COVID-19 in Lanzarote. It shows the main indicators and its daily evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
