<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Cazorla-Artiles JM</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/EITT%20logo_hu3c46a502bedc4e379e43c7b35d8f26ca_249766_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel de indicadores de COVID-19 en Lanzarote</title>
      <link>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A contribution made with Christian González-Martel to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cabildodelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cabildo de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;, this shiny web application pursues the understanding of the situation of COVID-19 in Lanzarote. It shows the main indicators and its daily evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel de indicadores de turismo de Lanzarote</title>
      <link>/project/panel_turismo_lanzarote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/panel_turismo_lanzarote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project pursues the improvement of tourism information to Lanzarote. With this objective a shiny web application was developed. The application collects data from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gobiernodecanarias.org/istac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ISTAC&lt;/a&gt; concerning to demand and supply of tourism in Canary Island and specially in Lanzarote. The data povided by the web application is related to arrivals, expenditure and occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is leaded by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datosdelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centro de datos de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt; the department of island council which provides with statistical information to Lanzarote and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ulpgc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria&lt;/a&gt; and funded by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cabildodelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cabildo de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was done with Christian González-Martel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>igebaser</title>
      <link>/project/igebaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/igebaser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ige&#34;&gt;IGE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galician Statistics Institute (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ige.eu/web/index.jsp?idioma=gl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Instituto Galego de Estatística, IGE&lt;/a&gt;) is an autonomous body of the Xunta de Galicia created in 1988 and which is governed basically by Law 9/1988 on Statistics of Galicia. In its mission to promote the development of the statistical system of the Autonomous Community must provide services of collection and dissemination of available statistical documentation, develop databases of public interest, analyze the needs and evolution of the demand for statistics and ensure their dissemination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;igebaser&#34;&gt;igebaser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The igebaser R-package allows researchers to quickly search and download the data of their particular interest in a programmatic and reproducible fashion; this facilitates a seamless integration into their workflow and allows analysis to be quickly rerun on different areas of interest and with realtime access to the latest available data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>istacbaser</title>
      <link>/project/istacbaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/istacbaser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;istac&#34;&gt;ISTAC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canary Islands Statistics Institute (
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gobiernodecanarias.org/istac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Instituto Canario de Estadítica, ISTAC&lt;/a&gt;) is the central organ of the autonomous statistical system and official research center of the Government of the Canary Islands, created and regulated by Law 1/1991 of 28 January, Statistics of the Autonomous Community of the Canary Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istacbaser&#34;&gt;istacbaser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The istacbaser R-package allows researchers to quickly search and download the data of their particular interest in a programmatic and reproducible fashion; this facilitates a seamless integration into their workflow and allows analysis to be quickly rerun on different areas of interest and with realtime access to the latest available data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
