<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Cazorla-Artiles</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/EITT%20logo_hu3c46a502bedc4e379e43c7b35d8f26ca_249766_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations dashboard for IS-LM model in an open economy</title>
      <link>/project/islm_economia_abierta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/islm_economia_abierta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This platform develops the Mundell-Fleming model, an open economy with perfect capital mobility is proposed, the fixed and flexible exchange rate scenarios are considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform supports the subject of international macroeconomics, as it allows the user to interact with it, establishing different economic policy scenarios and checking the results. The results shown are: the graphs of the IS-LM balance and the trade balance; and the main macroeconomic indicators before and after the change of scenery. In this way, the effectiveness of the different economic policies can be verified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Tourism Demand Model</title>
      <link>/project/itdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/itdm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This platform develops a methodology to anticipate international tourism demand by distinguishing the outbound market. The starting point is the construction of a baseline scenario that predicts the demand that would have occurred in 2020 and 2021 had the epidemic not existed. This baseline demand is affected by the situation with Covid-19 considering three effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The date of market reactivation according to the epidemic for each pair of origin-destination (based on an epidemiological SIR model);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reduction in income at origin and how it reduces the intention to travel (based on a panel data model);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reduction in confidence to travel (using post-pandemic travel surveys).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three effects reduce the expected pre-Covid19 demand and allow realistic adjustments according to the value of post-Covid expected demand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel de indicadores de COVID-19 en Lanzarote</title>
      <link>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/panel_covid19_lanzarote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A contribution made with Christian González-Martel to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cabildodelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cabildo de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;. This shiny web application pursues the understanding of the situation of COVID-19 in Lanzarote. It shows the main indicators and its daily evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel de indicadores de turismo de Lanzarote</title>
      <link>/project/panel_turismo_lanzarote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/panel_turismo_lanzarote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project pursues the improvement of tourism information to Lanzarote. A shiny web application is developed to collects data from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gobiernodecanarias.org/istac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ISTAC&lt;/a&gt; concerning demand and supply of tourism in Canary Islands and specially in Lanzarote. The data povided by the web application is related to arrivals, expenditure and occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is leaded by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datosdelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centro de datos de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt; which is the departament of Island Council which provides with statistical information to Lanzarote and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ulpgc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria&lt;/a&gt; and funded by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cabildodelanzarote.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cabildo de Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was done with Christian González-Martel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-Bridge</title>
      <link>/project/cbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cbridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ulpgc_slu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost-Benefit Analysis (CBA) has proved to be an appropriate method for assessing welfare impacts of infrastructure projects. Its main advantage relies on its capability for measuring the social benefits, which represents a step further from traditional income cash flow. Social benefits also account for intangibles, such as externalities, or willingness to pay, which may be higher than market prices. At the same time, it accounts for social costs, which take into account the opportunity costs that do not need to be the same as paid costs. One common approach taken is comparing surplus changes before and after a project infrastructure investment. Surpluses are usually measured for consumers, firms, workers, tax-payers and other agents or entities, such as the environment. CBA usually focuses on the primary market and the surplus changes can be calculated for all of them with relevant case study information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the infrastructure investment project has got implications on many sectors, the surplus calculations get more difficult to measure. Moreover, if the agents can obtain a benefit from the project implementation and it is translated into higher production, employment, capital rents or wages, an additional income effect is produced in other agents through additional consumption. In macroeconomic terms, the former effect is known as indirect effect, whereas the latter effect is known as induced effect. All these indirect and induced effects are usually missing in CBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessments (EIA) deal with macroeconomic impacts such as GDP or employment. A macroeconomic approach can be very useful for measuring the direct, indirect and the induced effects. Input-Output Analysis (IOA) employs sectorial matrices that relate all sectors in terms of inputs required to obtain certain outputs. It provides the key information to understand linkages among all sectors of the economy. Thus, the indirect effects can be measured. Additionally, Social Accounting Matrices (SAM) extend IOA to take into account income distribution. Thus, the induced effects can be measured. IOA and SAM show a static picture of the linkages of the economy, where constraints in resources are missing. In order to take into account such resource constraints, price and wage variations and its sensitivity, a Computable General Equilibrium (CGE) can be implemented. It extends the SAM and it employs elasticities and macroeconomic equations to describe the economic relationships. It allows for a better understanding of the dynamics of the economy over time. For this reason, this research proposal suggests employing CGE to measure indirect and induced effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge relies on how we can combine both tools. For instance, from a CBA perspective, an increase in GDP does not mean a homogeneous increase in social benefits. Moreover, an increase in employment is a positive output in EIA but a social cost in CBA terms. This research proposal tries to shed light on how this C-Bridge can be developed. The objective is twofold. On the one hand, a theoretical understanding of the bridge between CGE and CBA is pursued. On the other hand, empirical concerns are also considered, so that, at the end, divergence between CGE and CBA is identified and quantified depending on different market structure cases. The learning process consists of developing simple models which are controlled by alternative simulations. Later on, full models are also developed and simulations are run for three case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>igebaser</title>
      <link>/project/igebaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/igebaser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ige&#34;&gt;IGE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galician Statistics Institute (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ige.eu/web/index.jsp?idioma=gl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Instituto Galego de Estatística, IGE&lt;/a&gt;) is an autonomous body of the Xunta de Galicia created in 1988 and which is governed basically by Law 9/1988 on Statistics of Galicia. In its mission to promote the development of the statistical system of the Autonomous Community must provide services of collection and dissemination of available statistical documentation, develop databases of public interest, analyze the needs and evolution of the demand for statistics and ensure their dissemination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;igebaser&#34;&gt;igebaser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The igebaser R-package allows researchers to quickly search and download the data of their particular interest in a programmatic and reproducible fashion; this facilitates a seamless integration into their workflow and allows analysis to be quickly rerun on different areas of interest and with realtime access to the latest available data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>istacbaser</title>
      <link>/project/istacbaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/istacbaser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;istac&#34;&gt;ISTAC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canary Islands Statistics Institute (
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gobiernodecanarias.org/istac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Instituto Canario de Estadítica, ISTAC&lt;/a&gt;) is the central organ of the autonomous statistical system and official research center of the Government of the Canary Islands, created and regulated by Law 1/1991 of 28 January, Statistics of the Autonomous Community of the Canary Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;istacbaser&#34;&gt;istacbaser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The istacbaser R-package allows researchers to quickly search and download the data of their particular interest in a programmatic and reproducible fashion; this facilitates a seamless integration into their workflow and allows analysis to be quickly rerun on different areas of interest and with realtime access to the latest available data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
